This is the solutions video for calculating results.
本视频将讲解结果计算部分的答案
The first thing we need to do is define the calculate result_stats function.
首先 定义函数 calculates_results_stats
The doc string indicates that we'll have only one input parameter.
这里的文档字符串指出我们只有一个输入参数
This is results_dic.
即字典 results_dic
The dictionary with the image filename as its key,
该字典以图像文件名为键
and a list as its value.
以列表为值
Where the list contains the pet image label, the classifier label,
其列表值包括宠物图像标签、分类器标签
whether the labels match,
标签匹配结果
and whether the labels indicate the images are of dogs.
以及标签对图像是否为犬类的判定结果
This function returns the results_stats dictionary.
函数会返回字典 results_stats
This dictionary contains the counts and percentages that
该字典包含百分比和数量统计数据
summarize how well the algorithm did on classifying the images.
对算法的图像分类性能进行了汇总
First, we create an empty dictionary results_stats.
首先 创建一个空字典 results_stats
This dictionary will hold the counts in percentages.
该字典会将统计结果以百分比的形式记录下来
Next, we set all of our counters to zero.
接着 将所有计数器设为 0
We'll be counting the number of dog images,
以便统计犬类图像的数量
the number of matches,
匹配数量
the number of correctly classified dogs,
得到正确分类的犬类图像数量
the number of correctly classified non-dogs,
得到正确分类的非犬类图像数量
number of correctly classified breeds of dog.
以及犬种得到正确分类的图像的数量
Next, we'll be iterating through
接着 用 for 循环
the results_dic dictionary with a for loop incrementing these counters when appropriate.
对字典 results_dic 进行迭代 适时对这些计数器进行增量
If the labels match,
如果标签匹配
we'll increment the counter for the number of matches.
那就对匹配计数器 n_matches 进行增量
If both labels are of dogs and they match,
如果两个标签都为犬类而且相同
we'll increment the counter for the number of correctly classified breeds of dog.
那就意味着犬种得到了正确分类 我们要对相应的计数器 n_correct_breed 进行增量
If the pet label is a dog,
如果宠物标签为犬类
then we'll increment the counter for the number of dog images.
那就对犬类图像计数器 n_dogs_img 进行增量
If the classifier label is also of a dog,
如果分类器标签也为犬类
then we'll increment the number of correctly classified dogs.
那就是犬类图像得到了正确分类 我们要对相应的计数器 n_correct_dogs 进行增量
If the pet label is not a dog and the classifier label is not a dog,
如果宠物标签和分类器标签都不为犬类
then we'll increment the number of correctly classified non-dogs.
那就是非犬类图像得到了正确分类 于是给相应的计数器 n_correct_notdogs 进行增量
This ends the for loop that iterates through the results_dic dictionary.
至此 循环访问字典 results_dic 的 for 循环结束
Next, the number of total images is computed using the length of the results_dic.
接着 用 results_dic 的长度来计算总图像数
The number of non-dog images is computed using
非犬类图像数则等于
the number of images minus the number of dog images.
图像数减去犬类图像数
Next, we're going to compute all the percentages.
接着 计算各项百分比
The percentage match equals the number of
匹配百分比等于
matches divided by the number of images times 100.
匹配数 / 图像数 * 100
The percentage of correctly classified dogs is the number of
得到正确分类的犬类图像的百分比等于
correctly classified dogs divided by the number of dog images times 100.
得到正确分类的犬类图像数 / 犬类图像数 * 100
The percentage of correctly classified breeds is the number of
犬种得到正确分类的图像的百分比等于
correctly classified breeds divided by the number of dog images times 100.
犬种得到正确分类的图像数 / 犬类图像数 * 100
Finally, as long as we have at least one non-dog image,
最后 哪怕只有一张非犬类图像
we'll compute the percentage of correctly classified non-dogs as the number of
我们都要计算得到正确分类的非犬类图像的百分比
correctly classified non-dogs divided by the number of non-dog images times 100.
也即得到正确分类的非犬类图像数 / 非犬类图像数 * 100
If there are no non-dog images,
如果没有非犬类图像
this percentage is set to zero.
那就将该百分比设为 0
At the bottom of this function,
在函数底部
we'll return this results_stats dictionary.
返回字典 results_stats
This is the function call to
在主函数里
the calculate results_stats function within the main function.
我们调用了函数 calculates_results_stats
This function returns the result_stats_dic dictionary that contains
该函数会返回字典 results_stats_dic
the percentages and counts that summarize how well the algorithm classifies the images.
该字典包含各项百分比和数量统计 对算法的图像分类效果进行了汇总
This dictionary has a key that's
这个字典以统计数据名为键
the statistics name and a value that's the statistics value.
以统计数据值为值
This function has one input argument, result_dic.
函数有一个输入参数 即字典 result_dic
This is the dictionary that was returned by adjust-results4-isadog function.
该字典由函数 adjust-results4-isadog 返回而出
This dictionary has the image file name as its key and a list as its value.
以图像文件名为键 以列表为值
The list contains the pet image labels, the classifier labels,
其列表值包括宠物图像标签、分类器标签
whether the labels match,
标签匹配结果
whether the labels indicate the images are of dogs.
以及标签对图像是否为犬类的判定结果
We use this temporary code here to check our code.
使用这里的临时代码来检查代码效果
We'll be recomputing some counts and percentages using result_dic dictionary.
用字典 result_dic 重新计算一些数量统计和百分比数据
We'll then compare these counts and percentages to the counts and percentages that were
然后将所得数据和百分比
produced by the results_stats_dic dictionary that was returned by our function.
与由函数返回的字典 results_stats_dic  生成的相应数据进行比较
We'll visually check to do this comparison.
要进行比较
Let's look at our code in the terminal window.
我们可以来到终端窗口 观察代码
Here we've run the check images Python program.
这里运行了程序 check_images.py
Here are the statistics from our function.
这是函数的统计数据
Here are the statistics from the temporary code.
这是临时代码的统计数据
We can see that they match.
两者一致
So, we know our code has run properly.
可见代码无误